flipitphysics.com 2016-03-27

# Privacy Policy

Macmillan Higher Education respects your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you. This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on our Web sites, how we may use that information, and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. In addition, we describe the choices you can make about how we use the information you provide to us. We also tell you how you can reach us to update your contact information, contact us with general questions or comments, inquire about our company and its products and services, or answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices. 

* * *

### Information We Collect  

###### Examination Copies  

Instructors may request examination copies of textbooks and some supplements from our Web sites. Instructors may also request preview access to password-protected areas of our Web sites. In order to fulfill these requests, we will need to collect information that will allow us to confirm your instructor status. This may include information such as your name, e-mail address, telephone number, the school at which you teach, your course and the book or product you are using in it. 

###### Adopting Instructor Support  

We offer a number of Web-based products and services to adopting instructors. A user account is necessary to get support for these products and services. To create a user account, you will need to enter your name and e-mail address. You will also need to establish a password of your choosing. We may require additional information to confirm your status as an adopting instructor, e.g., your school name and location, course information, including the textbook you are using, and a telephone number where we can contact you. In addition, you may choose to provide optional information (e.g., your areas of interest), which will allow us to serve you better. 

###### Student Grades and Work  

Many of our Web sites allow students to do and save work over the Internet (e.g., iSolve, Comment, and exercises and quizzes on our book-specific Web sites). Both instructors and students create user accounts by entering their name and e-mail address, and establishing a password. Each student generally has access to his or her own work or scores only; instructors can only access work or scores of students in their courses. In some instances, however, instructors may have the ability to require students to work collaboratively, in which case students may be able to view, and in some instances comment upon, the work of others. 

Protection of information entered by students on such sites is controlled by password systems that depend upon both instructors and students keeping their passwords secure. In the event that providing technical or user support requires accessing student work to diagnose or fix the problem, Macmillan Higher Education will only take that step with permission from the student and/or instructor involved. 

###### Sweepstakes, Contests and Other Promotions  

From time to time we may run sweepstakes, contests or other promotions on our Web sites. If you choose to participate, we may request your contact and other information in connection with the promotion. 

###### Surveys and Questionnaires  

We may ask visitors to our Web sites to complete online surveys and opinion polls on a variety of topics, such as their activities, attitudes, and interests, and our products and services. These surveys help us understand the needs of our visitors. 

###### Chat Rooms, Forums, Blogs and Discussion Groups  

We may host chat rooms, forums, blogs and/or discussion groups (including by e-mail, bulletin board, instant messaging or other technologies) on our own or on third-party Web sites. If you choose to participate in a chat room, forum, blog or discussion group, we may request certain information such as your e-mail address, date of birth, academic status and affiliation, and other pertinent information. Please be aware that some or all the information you provide (including personally identifiable information such as your name) in connection with a chat room, forum, blog or discussion group may be available to specific groups or to the public generally, depending upon the technologies used. 

###### "Contact Us" and Technical Support  

You may choose to contact us through our Web site. If you e-mail us comments or questions, we will have your e-mail address, as well as any other information you choose to provide. 

###### Send This Page to a Friend  

You may choose to use our "Send This Page to a Friend" service, which lets you send either a copy of the page or selected content from it, or the URL for that page, to people you believe will find the information useful. These services will require you to enter the e-mail address(es) of the intended recipient(s). In these instances, the e-mail addresses provided will not be added to any marketing or outreach database. They will be counted and studied in aggregate to look for broad trends, but then deleted from the "Send a Page to a Friend" dataset. However, such addresses may already be in our databases from some other source. 

###### Buying our Products  

We sometimes offer our books and other products for sale on-line directly to students. In order to make a purchase in this way, you will need to register directly with PayPal, a third-party service provider we use to process the purchase. When you do this, you will be their customer as well as ours, and use of your information by PayPal will be governed by their privacy policy, as well as by ours. 

###### Cookies  

We use cookies on our Web sites (including the companion Web sites for some of our books), to help us administer certain site features (such as the Comment system). Cookies are small text files that Web sites often store on the computer hard drives of visitors to their sites. A cookie contains a unique code, which is used to recognize a computer when a user of that computer returns to a Web site that was visited previously. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. However, in order to use certain features of our Web sites, users must have the "cookie" function on their browsers enabled. 

###### Other Passive Collection Information  

When you visit our Web site, your browser automatically sends us certain Internet-related information, such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you're using and your originating domain. 

We use log files to collect certain aggregate information about Web site use, such as how many users visited our site, the average time spent on the site and the pages viewed. This site also uses ClickTale web analytics service. ClickTale may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity, as well as any text you type in this website. ClickTale does not collect personally identificable information that you do not voluntarily enter in this Web site. By collecting these types of information, we learn how best to tailor our Web sites to our visitors. While we generally examine such information only in the aggregate, such information could be linked back to individual IP addresses. In addition, if you are a registered user of one of our Web sites, this information will be associated with your user name or id. 

###### Location of Data Storage and Processing  

Macmillan Higher Education  is headquartered in the United States.  When you provide your personal information to us through our websites, your data will be stored on our servers, and on the servers of our affiliates and service providers, which may be located in the United States or elsewhere.  As a result, if you are located outside the United States, your personal information may be transmitted to, and stored and processed in, a country other than the one in which you reside.  If you reside in Canada, the European Union (EU), or any other jurisdiction with regulations governing the transfer of personal data to other jurisdictions, by registering on our site and agreeing to these terms, YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE TRANSFER, STORAGE AND PROCESSING OF THE PERSONAL DATA YOU SUBMIT THROUGH OUR SITE IN COUNTRIES OUTSIDE CANADA, THE EU OR THE COUNTRY IN WHICH YOU RESIDE, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION IN THE UNITED STATES.  If you do not agree to provide such consent, you may not register with this site or access the services and products available through this site. 

Although we, Macmillan Higher Education, will not permit registration on our site or use of our services without your Agreement to our Legal Terms, if you are a student located outside the United States and you decline acceptance of our Legal Terms, we will permit your registration using an alias. If you wish to register using an alias, you will need to create an alias and create and open an e-mail account under that alias with a third-party email service.  Next, when you register on our site you will do so by providing your alias and the email address you've opened under that alias. You will be required to accept our Legal Terms as part of the registration process, which you will complete under your Alias. IT IS CRITICAL THAT YOU MAKE SURE YOU INFORM YOUR INSTRUCTOR OF YOUR ALIAS SO THAT HE/SHE HAS ACCESS TO YOUR WORK. Do NOT provide Macmillan Higher Education  with any information that would enable us to link your alias to your real personal information 

### How We Use Information We Collect  

Information collected through our Web sites is used in connection with the purpose for which it was submitted (for example, to contact you if you win a sweepstakes or contest, to allow you to participate in a chat room, to contact you with an answer to a question, or to send you information or a product you've requested). 

We may also contact you as a user of one of our products to: ask you to serve as a reviewer; to request an appointment with you at your campus or at a conference to talk about an existing or planned product; and other similar kinds of feedback and discussion. We may also use the information we collect to send you information or products we think may be of interest to you, and to customize our contacts with you. 

Finally, we may use some of the information we collect to analyze Web site use and to do other internal analyses, such as market research, that will allow us to better meet the needs of our customers. 

We do not sell, rent, trade or otherwise disclose personal information about our Web site visitors, except as described here. If we describe more limited sharing practices in connection with your use of a specific product or service anywhere on our Web sites, those more limited practices will apply as to that product or service only. We may share the information you provide with companies that are related to Macmillan Higher Education through common ownership. We also share information provided by our Web site visitors with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf. In addition, we may share information about you with non-affiliated third parties whose products or services may be of interest to you. These third parties may contact you about their products and services. We will not share your information with these third parties for their own marketing purposes if you request that we not do so. We may, however, engage in joint marketing activities, such as contests or promotions, with selected third parties and may share personal information about our Web site visitors with them. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, (ii) in response to legal process, (iii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iv) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. 

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the transferee uses personal information you have provided through this Web site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice. 

### Links to Other Web sites  

We provide links to other Web sites for your convenience. Also, on occasion, we may provide to a department, program, class or instructor access to a third-party Web site (which may also include access to third-party software). These sites may operate independently from Macmillan Higher Education, and may not be under our control. These sites may have their own privacy notices in place, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked Web sites. We may not be responsible for the content of these sites, any products or services that may be offered through these sites, or the privacy practices of these sites. 

### Security  

We use administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect information in our possession and control against foreseeable hazards. Please note, however, that perfect security does not exist on the Internet 

### Your Choices About Marketing  

We give you the option of requesting that we not share personal information about you with third parties that are unrelated by common ownership with Macmillan Higher Education for marketing use.  [Click here](mailto:preferences@macmillan.com?subject=Do%20not%20share%20my%20personal%20information%20with%20unrelated%20third%20parties) if you DO NOT want us to share your personal information with unrelated third parties for their own marketing use. 

We also give you the option of requesting that we not share your information with companies related to Macmillan Higher Education by common ownership for marketing use. However, PLEASE NOTE that, because of the integrated nature of the businesses of Macmillan Higher Education and some of these companies, if you opt out of sharing with them, you will also automatically be opted out of marketing use by Macmillan Higher Education. That means that you will not receive information about books, new products, promotions and services from Macmillan Higher Education.  [Click here](mailto:preferences@macmillan.com?subject=Do%20not%20share%20my%20personal%20information%20with%20any%20affiliated%20parties) if you do not want us to share your information with related companies for marketing use (or use the information for marketing purposes ourselves). (Keep in mind, however, that some of our related companies may have independently obtained your information, in which case you may continue to receive communications from those companies, unless you opt out directly with them.) 

[Please be aware that we are able to effectuate an opt-out only for a specific e-mail address, or for a name and address or other identifying information. For example, we are unable to opt out "John Smith" by name alone, because of the large number of persons by that name in our databases. So, if you have more than one e-mail address, if you move or change jobs, or if the information you provide us when opting out doesn't match the information in our databases, your opt out request may not be effectuated properly. If you believe you have opted out, but continue to receive e-mails from us, please contact us by one of the means listed under "How to Contact Us", below, and we will endeavor to resolve the issue.] 

### Updates to this Privacy Notice  

We may change or update portions of this Privacy Notice at any time and without prior notice to you. Please check back from time to time so you are aware of any changes or updates to the Notice. We will indicate above the effective date of the Notice. 

### How to Contact Us  

If you would like to update your contact information, click here. If you have any questions about our information practices or our products or services, please contact us by: 

  * writing us at:   
Macmillan Higher Education 41 Madison Avenue New York, NY 10010Attention: WebStaff
